here's a quick video to show you how to
get the bar onto your hips during the
hip thrust so here I've got 135 lbs
loaded up and I've got a bar pad I'm
using the hip Thruster here which is
about 16 in high so with this I can just
roll the bar over my legs and then
squeeze into position okay and
then thrust so this is very easy this
way
now what
if what if you're not strong enough to
use 135 lb well there's going to be two
options which I'm going to show
you if you're not strong enough to use
135 LBS or 60 kgs if you train in a
country that uses kilograms then the
best option is to have bumper plates so
these are 25 lb plates but they're the
same height the same size as the 45 lb
plate or the the 20 kg plate so in this
situation you just again roll the bar
over into
position hip thrust you also make these
in even smaller increments for example
here's a a 10 lb plate and you can use
this instead so ideally your gym has
bumper plates but probably doesn't so
I'm going to show you another
option so chances are uh you train it a
gym and they don't have bumper plates
they have plates like this smaller
plates so you can't get under it so in
that situation here's what you're going
to do you are going
to deadlift the bar up kind of situate
it near your lap and then sit
gently and then I'm just going to slide
into place like
this from
here finish my set scoot back
up like
this stand back up put it down so that's
a good option that's what most of you're
going to do until you get to where
you're using 135 lb so I can usually get
my girls hip thrusting 135 lb within
four to six weeks even 60y olds even
beginners so if you're aggressive you
can you don't you won't have to deal
with this weight forever it's only a
temporary fix until you're strong enough
to use the bigger
plates now some of you uh stronger and
more advanced ladies might have this
situation and even some
men here I've got a very tall bench and
a lot of gyms have benches that are
really tall like this is too high for me
to hip thrust
from so you might roll the bar over get
into position and you might notice that
this is not in good back placement so in
this case you've got to climb up this
kind of sucks but you get used to it
over time I'll put my elbows on
and just kind of get my feet wedged into
place and a lot of shorter women and
then women with shorter torsos have to
do this but uh you just have to get
comfortable kind of going like this and
lifting your body up getting into proper
position and then from
here doing your
set and then come down and wow so I hope
you enjoyed the video remember start out
with body weight get comfortable with
the
movement then use the bar and then move
up gradually over time within six months
I get most of my ladies to be hip
thrusting 225 lbs for 10 reps not all of
them but most of them and some of them
um can do 315 lbs for 10 rep so it's a
very very strong powerful movement it's
a great movement for the glutes best of
luck